Leifur Castle - Web Developer

(208) 310-2163 · leifurcastle@gmail.com · Ferndale, Wa · https://leifurcastle.com

Web Developer from General Assembly with expertise in JavaScript and Python, and experience creating applications with frameworks such as Next, React, and Django. Strong problem-solving skills coupled with a background in customer service and team leadership enhances ability to deliver outstanding results.

Skills

Languages - JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS, SQL

Libraries and Frameworks - React, Next, Django, NodeJS, Express.js, Tailwind CSS

Database/Other - MongoDB, Mongoose, Postgres, Sequelize, Selenium, Git, Github, Postman, Twilio, Courier

Software Development Projects

BirthdayBuzz (In Progress) - www.birthdaybuz.net Automated birthday email reminder tool August 2023 - Present

- Frontend built with Next and JavaScript, user accounts require email verification implemented with Twilio's API
- Back-end RESTful API server built with NodeJS, Express.js, and MongoDB Atlas cloud database
- Utilized MongoDB & Mongoose to allow users to save friends and family to their "Buzz List"
- Integrated Heroku's app Cron To Go to run daily scripts fulfilling each users' Buzz List reminder requests
- Automatic emailing implemented with Courier's service API
- Frontend to backend seamless communication achieved with Axios HTTP requests, often sent with accompanying data in JSON format, and user authentication implemented with passport.js
- Collaborated with the team as a Git Master using Git forking workflow procedures and frequent commits
- Successfully deployed backend and frontend to Heroku with a custom domain (www.birthdaybuz.net)

Colorz - www.colorznow.com Layout based theme creation tool

July 2023 - August 2023

- Utilized Next and JavaScript to create a dynamic front-end application boasting user accounts, wireframing tools, color and styling options, and user theme to CSS color pallet exportation
- Employed React hooks to create drag & drop resizable widgets capable of quickly wireframing an existing or new website's basic layout and text
- Full background, text, and font customization enables users to immediately visualize how color choices would look on their website through the wireframe's representation.
- Implemented a back-end RESTful API server using NodeJS and Express.js and an integrated MongoDB database
- Enabled users to save themes to a User model of multi-level embedded documents with MongoDB & Mongoose
- Achieved seamless front to backend communication with Axios and user authentication with passport.js
- Collaborated with the team as a Git Master using Git forking workflow procedures and frequent commits
- Successfully deployed backend and frontend to Heroku with a custom domain (www.colorznow.com)

Professional Experience

The Home Depot | Bellingham, Wa - Head Cashier/Service Desk/Pro

May 2023 - Present

- Led and supervised a team of cashiers, ensuring accurate and efficient transactions, and providing excellent customer service. Expertise in cash handling, inventory management, and loss prevention. Provided coaching and assistance to cashiers fostering positive customer experiences and driving customer satisfaction.
- Attained mastery in operating Home Depot's software systems as a cashier, service desk representative, pro associate, and paint associate, resulting in efficient and accurate customer transactions.

JDP Renovations - Lead Laborer | Moscow, Id

Oct 2020 - June 2022

• Led a small team of two in renovations/additions for three houses, teaching both coworkers rudimentary carpentry, trim, plumbing, electrical, and tool skills along the way

Education

General Assembly | Remote Software Engineering Immersive

Feb 2023 - August 2022

Full-stack software engineering immersive 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies.